Guide to the John Punnett Peters Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1889, 1915-1981, undated; Accession 1991-M-035; 1.50 linear feet (4 boxes)
  - Peters, John Punnett
    - Writings
      - Quantitative Clinical Chemistry Memorabilia 1931-1934: A Collection of Letters, Advertisements and Reviews of Quantitative Clinical Chemistry (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Loose papers found in Quantitative Clinical Chemistry Memorabilia, 1931-1932, 1935, 1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - "A Petition to the president of the United States;" a petition re: the Employee Security Program (Acc 91-M-54), 1955 May (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Memorabilia, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Peters, Charlotte (Hodge)
    - Correspondence/general files
      - General/family, 1919, 1927, 1937-1938, 1945, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Irwin, Alice (Peters) (daughter), 1939, 1942, 1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Bowles, Chester, 1948-1949, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1944 November 4 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Condolences on the death of J.P.P., 1955 December-1956 Mar, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Publications attributed to Charlotte Hodge Peters as author, editor, and compiler, 1933, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Legal documents, 1889, 1929, 1944, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Appointment books, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Appointment books, 1940-1950 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Newspaper clippings found in appointment books, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Irwin, Alice Peters
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1949, 1955-1956, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Condolences on the death of her father, 1955 December 29-1956 May 6, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Attempt to obtain FBI and CIA files of her parents, 1975, 1977-1978, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Other materials
      - other materials Newspaper clippings, 1955-1956, 1973, n.d (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Miscellaneous, 1953, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Photographs, 1922, 1945, 1948, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Genealogy prepared by Diane E. Taylor, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - "In Search of the Nippur Archives or, How to Excavate Attics," by Diane E. Taylor, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Fiftieth congratulatory messages of J.P.P. (Acc 91-M-62), 1937 December 4 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Additional Material, 1917-1954, undated; Accession 1993-M-043; 1.25 linear feet (4 boxes, 1 folio)
  Addition inventory by Carol King, 1993 Feb
  Received from: Alice Irwin, 1993 Jan 29
  - Peters, John Punnett
    - Correspondence
      - General/family, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Peters, Charlotte Hodge (wife), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
      - Peters, Charlotte Hodge, 1918, 1926-1927, 1938-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7-13)
      - Irwin, Alice Peters (daughter), 1954 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Peters, Mrs. John Punnett, Sr. (mother), 1918 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Wartime patients/colleagues, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - General files
      - American Expeditionary Forces: bulletins, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Diary of John Punnett Peters, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - "The Dooins," newsletter of U.S. Reserve Base Hospital No. 2, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
      - Medical memoranda, reports, 1917-1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Military Orders, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Printed material, newspaper clippings, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Theater programs, menus, 1917-1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Album of wartime memorabilia, photographs, and postcards, 1917-1919 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - Sketches (laid in) (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Album of wartime newspaper and magazine clippings, 1917-1919, n.d (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Peters, Charlotte Hodge
    - Correspondence
      - General/family, 1917, 1928, 1937-1946 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Peters, John Punnett, 1917-1918, 1932, undated (Box 4, Folder 29-39)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1946-1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - "Applications of Gas Analysis," by Yandell Henderson: hand written copy by [CHP?], 1917 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Peters, Mrs. John Punnett, Sr. (mother)
    - John Punnett Peters, [n.y.] September 20 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Peters, Frazier F.
    - Correspondence to his mother, 1918 September 4 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Degrees and certificated of John Punnett Peters
    - American Board of Internal Medicine, 1936 December 1 (Box 5)
    - National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 1947 April 30 (Box 5)
    - Royal Society of Medicine, 1951 October 23 (Box 5)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-035
  - Peter, John P., Jr.
    - Correspondence
      - General, Circa 1934-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Peters, John P., Sr., 1900-1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Memorabilia, 1913-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Peters, Charlotte Hodge [letters to her children]
    - Peters, John Hodge, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Peters, Richard Morse, Circa 1941-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
- Additional Material, 1931-2004; Accession 2005-M-076
  - FBI materials
    - Correspondence to and from Richard M. Peters (son of John Punnett Peters), 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - FBI FOIA Report, 1948 July 23 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 7)
  - Correspondence
    - John Hodge Peters (son of John Punnett Peters) to and from his parents, 1931-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 11)
    - John Hodge Peters to his mother (Charlotte H. Peters), 1942, 1944, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 12 - 14)
    - John Punnett Peters to John Hodge Peters, 1948-1953 (Box 2, Folder 15 - 20)
    - Carol M. Sax to John Hodge Peters, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Additional Material, 1924-2006; Accession 2007-M-027
  - Certificate and contract, personal, 1926, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1951, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Family of Non-Conformists," by Richard Morse Peters, edited by Joan F. Peters
    - Volumes 1 and 2, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
    - FBI files about John Punnett Peters used by Richard Morse Peters, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation Freedom of Information Act files
    - Association of Interns and Medical Students, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 6 - 8)
    - Association of Interns and Medical Students, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Official Report of Proceedings before the Loyalty Review Board of the U. S. Civil Service Commission, 1953 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "John Punnett Peters Loyalty Travails," by Richard Morse Peters [includes notes and excerpts of loyalty letters, 1945-1955], 1945-1955, 2003 February (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Trial transcript of John P. Peters, petitioner, v. Oveta Culp Hobby, et al., respondents, 1955 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, circa 1948-1956; Accession 2007-M-082
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) files
    - 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
    - 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Loyalty Board testimony
    - 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9 - 10)
    - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Civil Service Commission files
    - Circa 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 12 - 13)
    - Circa 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)